The Second Renaissance Part I is a science fiction,
animation film directed by Mahiro Maeda.
Tells the early history of how conflict began between the humans and machines.
Part 1 of 2.
The Instructor (voice), played by Julia Fletcher.
01 Versatran Spokesman (voice), played by Dane A. Davis.
Kid (voice), played by Debi Derryberry.
Mother (voice) / Additional Voices (voice), played by Jill Talley.
Additional Voices (voice), played by Dwight Schultz.
Additional Voices (voice), played by James Arnold Taylor.
Renaissance: A Film by Beyoncé is a 2023 American documentary
concert film written, directed, and produced by Beyoncé.
Similar to Homecoming: A Film by Beyoncé (2019), the film chronicles the development and execution of her
2023 Renaissance World Tour, conducted to support her seventh studio album Renaissance (2022).
Beyoncé signed a distribution agreement with AMC Theatres and announced the
concert film after concluding the tour in Kansas City, Missouri.
The film depicts the creation of Renaissance and the production of the tour.
Her family members, namely husband Jay-Z, parents Mathew and Tina Knowles, cousin Angela
Beyincé, and three children Blue Ivy, Rumi, and Sir Carter are featured in the film.
Diana Ross, Megan Thee Stallion, and Kendrick Lamar are featured in musical performances; former Destiny's Child members Kelly
Rowland, Michelle Williams, LaTavia Roberson, and LeToya Luckett make brief appearances throughout the film.
The end credits feature "My House", a 2023 single
by Beyoncé in support of the film.
The film premiered at the Samuel Goldwyn Theater in Los Angeles on November 25,
2023, before the theatrical release in the United States on December 1.
The film received universal praise from critics and fans alike, who praised the concert footage, production,
behind-the-scenes elements and Beyoncé's stage presence, and has grossed over $44 million at the global box office.
The tone is thought_provoking.